A quest.
Knight of Cups is a drama, romance film directed by Terrence Malick.
Rick is a screenwriter living in Los Angeles.
While successful in his career, his life feels empty.
Haunted and confused, he finds temporary solace in the decadent
Hollywood excess that defines his existence.
Women provide a distraction to his daily pain, and every encounter
brings him closer to finding his place in the world.
Rick, played by Christian Bale.
Nancy, played by Cate Blanchett.
Elizabeth, played by Natalie Portman.
Joseph, played by Brian Dennehy.
Tonio, played by Antonio Banderas.
Helen, played by Freida Pinto.
Knight of Cups is a 2015 American romantic drama film
written and directed by Terrence Malick.
Starring Christian Bale, Cate Blanchett, and Natalie Portman, film follows Rick (Bale), a hedonistic screenwriter who goes on an odyssey through Los Angeles and Las
Vegas as he undertakes a series of adventures with several people, including his ex-wife Nancy (Blanchett) and his married lover Elizabeth (Portman).
The film is loosely inspired by, and at times quotes directly from, the 1678 Christian allegory The Pilgrim's
Progress, the Acts of Thomas passage "Hymn of the Pearl", and Suhrawardi's A Tale of the Western Exile.
Each of the characters is identified by a tarot card from the Major
Arcana, with Bale representing the Knight of Cups.
Knight of Cups premiered at the 65th Berlin International Film Festival on
February 8, 2015, where it was nominated for the Golden Bear.
The film was theatrically released in the United States on March 4, 2016, to mixed reviews from critics, with
several finding the narrative structure incoherent, while others praised the visual style.
The film explores themes of dreams, midlife crisis,
screenwriter, creative crisis, success.
The tone is emotional and thought_provoking.